mredllc.com 2017-12-16

# Midwest Real Estate Data LLC

We at Midwest Real Estate Data ("MRED") LLC, your Multiple Listing Service, are posting our Internet Privacy Policy to let you, our members, know that we take privacy and information security seriously. We have a firm commitment to the privacy and security of the information provided by you at our website and MRED is in the process of establishing Fair Information Practice Policies focused on carefully managing data so as to be in compliance with all applicable laws and industry guidelines. You, our Members, should be aware of the issues surrounding privacy and information security with regard to your client's information and that they may have an impact on your business practices. 

Please read this Privacy Policy to learn more. This Policy applies to the use of this site by our Members. Since technology has become such an integral part of our business in the last few years and has really changed many aspects of the real estate transaction, we are proud to offer up-to-date services to our Members through this website. We are here to help you in a variety of ways including providing your listings to visitors searching the Internet for Chicago real estate. 

#### INFORMATION COLLECTED ON THIS WEBSITE: 

Automatic Collection of Anonymous Information. When you enter the MREDLLC.com website, like when you visit most other websites, certain anonymous information about your visit is automatically logged. This may include information about the type of browser you use, the server name and IP (Internet Protocol) address through which you access the Internet, the date and time you access the site, the pages you access or, if you linked to the website from another, the Internet address of that website may be captured and logged. None of this information is personally identifiable. You are traveling the website anonymously until you access the MRED Members Only (Secure Access Only) portion of the website. When you Log In with your Member ID# and your Password, you must allow us to set a "Cookie" (see "Cookies" below) in order to verify that your Member ID# and Password match and that you are an authorized user of the Member services available. At that point we know it is you, or it should be you, and no other, as sharing your Member ID# and Password access information is a violation of the terms of our Agreement for use of the Multiple Listing Services. At that point we have personally identifiable information based on our records about you. 

##### Personally Identifiable Information

Personally identifiable information is any information that concerns you, individually, and would permit someone to contact you, for example, your name, address, telephone number, social security number, email address or any information you submit that identifies you individually. 

##### Cookies

The MRED website's server, or the servers of companies that are used to operate this site, may place a "Cookie" on your computer in order to allow you to use the website and, in a Member's case, to allow you access to the various systems and services behind our "Members Only" wall. A "Cookie" is a small piece of data that is sent by a web server to your computer, which then may be stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies allow us to recognize your computer while you are on our website. Cookies are useful in allowing us to track where you go on our site. It helps us improve the functionality of our website by knowing what our Members use and do not use. Most web browser applications (such as Microsoft Internet Explorer and Netscape Navigator) have features that can notify you when you receive a cookie or prevent cookies from being sent but, as said above, you do need to allow cookies to enter the Members Only portion of the website. 

##### EXTERNAL LINKS 

The MRED.com website contains links to other websites, Realtor® Associations and MRED Marketing Partners just to name a few. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices, information security or business practices of other websites. Websites that are accessible by links from our website may use Cookies (see "Cookies" above). We encourage you to read the privacy statements provided by other websites before you provide personally identifiable information to them. 

##### SECURITY

MRED LLC. maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to help guard all of the information contained in our database. The servers hosting our website are behind a firewall and are monitored 24 hours per day, 7 days a week. We restrict authorized access to those persons who have a legitimate purpose to know the information in our database and the hardware and software systems we use. Please be aware, however, that any email or other transmission you send through the Internet cannot be completely protected against unauthorized interception and, therefore, is not secure. 

#### HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION: 

Our Members need to know, we do not sell, rent, or exchange any data about you. We have many uses for the data for Member services, such as our Member Directory, but we do not sell, rent or exchange any data you provide through this website. 

That said, our lawyer told us that we must say we may disclose, transfer, sell or assign information obtained through this website, or otherwise in our possession, to third parties as a result of a sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of substantial assets, reorganization or liquidation of MRED LLC. or we may be required to make such information available to law enforcement personnel and agencies when requested to do so or as required by law. 

#### PRIVACY STATEMENT CHANGES: 

MRED LLC. reserve the right to change or amend its Members' Privacy Statement to address new issues of privacy and information security and to reflect changes to our website or business practices. Any new changes and/or amendments will be noted on our Home Page and will always be posted in this section of the MRED.com website. 

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT OUR PRIVACY STATEMENT? 

If you have any questions about this Members' Privacy Statement or the practices of this website, you can send an e-mail to: [privacy@MREDLLC.com](mailto:privacy@MREDLLC.com).
